Mischief. Mayhem. Soap.
Fight Club is a drama, thriller film directed by David Fincher.
A ticking-time-bomb insomniac and a slippery soap salesman channel
primal male aggression into a shocking new form of therapy.
Their concept catches on, with underground "fight clubs" forming in every town, until an
eccentric gets in the way and ignites an out-of-control spiral toward oblivion.
Narrator, played by Edward Norton.
Tyler Durden, played by Brad Pitt.
Marla Singer, played by Helena Bonham Carter.
Robert Paulson, played by Meat Loaf.
Angel Face, played by Jared Leto.
Richard Chesler (Regional Manager), played by Zach Grenier.
Fight Club is a 1999  American film directed by David Fincher and
starring Brad Pitt, Edward Norton, and Helena Bonham Carter.
It is based on the 1996 novel by Chuck Palahniuk.
Norton plays the unnamed narrator, who is
discontented with his white-collar job.
He forms a "fight club" with a soap salesman, Tyler Durden (Pitt), and becomes embroiled
with an impoverished but beguiling woman, Marla Singer (Bonham Carter).
Palahniuk's novel was optioned by Fox 2000 Pictures producer Laura
Ziskin, who hired Jim Uhls to write the film adaptation.
Fincher was selected because of his enthusiasm for the story.
He developed the script with Uhls and sought screenwriting advice
from the cast and others in the film industry.
It was filmed in and around Los Angeles from July to December 1998.
He and the cast compared the film to Rebel Without a Cause (1955) and The Graduate (1967), with
a theme of conflict between Generation X and the value system of advertising.
Studio executives did not like the film and restructured Fincher's
intended marketing campaign to try to reduce anticipated losses.
Fight Club premiered at the 56th Venice International Film Festival on September 10, 1999, and
was released in the United States on October 15, 1999, by 20th Century Fox.
The film failed to meet the studio's expectations at
the box office and polarized critics.
It was ranked as one of the most controversial and
talked-about films of the 1990s.
However, Fight Club later found commercial success with its home video release,
establishing it as a cult classic and causing media to revisit the film.
In 2009, on its tenth anniversary, The New York Times dubbed
it the "defining cult movie of our time".
The film explores themes of dual identity, rage and hate,
based on novel or book, nihilism, fight.
The tone is emotional and intense.